[CARLA]
Eren--
You want them to think
that you're strong?
Exercise restraint.
Try protecting Mikasa
once in a while.
[EREN]
Stop it! No!
[Gasps]
♪ Opening Song ♪
He tossing Titans now?
That son of a bitch
has gone berserk!
[REINER TITAN roars]
[JEAN grunts]
[YMIR]
Damn you, Commander Erwin!
I had this all planned out.
Why'd you have to go
and screw it up?
[Gasps]
[CHRISTA]
Ymir! Conny! Over there!
I see!
Commander!
[ERWIN]
I'm not your objective.
Don't waste time on
someone who's replaceable.
Retrieve Eren and go.
[MALE SOLDIER 37A screams]
[MIKASA]
Get down!
[HANNES grunts]
Are you insane?
[Yells]
[Laughs]
Can you believe this luck?
Ha! Crazy, right?
Watch me! This is the least
that I owe your mother.
She'll finally have
the vengeance she deserves!
[Yells]
No! Hannes!
[JEAN]
He needs backup!
[ARMIN yells]
[ARMIN]
Reiner. What the--?
Doesn't he care
if Eren gets eaten?
Move it or lose it, asshole!
I'm tired of your shit!
What are you doing?
[YMIR]
Honestly? Hell if I know.
Do I trust Reiner,
or gamble on the Scouts
and hope for the best?
[Grunts]
[YMIR] Suppose I actually
manage to live through this.
What good's another day
on borrowed time?
Life inside the walls
will be a nightmare.
That's a fact.
This may be my only shot
at bringing her over
to the other side.
I'm just one person.
I can't protect her forever.
Christa!
No. No more.
Sorry, from now on
I'm Historia.
Okay, so tell me.
What did you mean exactly
by "handing me over"?
Would it really have saved you,
or was that a lie?
Stupid question.
Of course it was.
Why, then?
Why go to the trouble?
Was it me?
You were trying
to protect me again!
[CONNY]
Heads up!
Listen to me. You need
to take your own advice.
You understand me?
Stop putting
yourself on the line!
You need to live your
own life! Live it with me!
I never told you this before,
but however bad things get,
as long as we're together...
...I'm not afraid!
[Yells]
[EREN] Mikasa, stop!
You're in no shape to--!
My hands! Help me!
What'll you do?
[EREN]
Come on!
I have to be the one
who kills that thing!
[Grunts]
I ain't done with you yet!
This one belongs to me!
Wait here.
Eren! Don't go! We have to
get you out of here!
Not until I've settled
the score. Stand back.
[Gasps]
[EREN]
What?
[MALE SOLDIER 37B yells]
[MALE SOLDIER 37C]
Commander!
Sir! The Armored!
It's coming this way!
[Gasps]
Jean!
[JEAN grunts]
[Groans]
[ARMIN]
No!
Oh god. Stay with me, Jean!
[Yells]
[EREN]
No! Don't do this!
Not now!
Eren, stop!
[EREN growls]
[ARMIN yells]
[Yells]
[PEER screams]
Commander!
[Yells]
[Gasps]
[HANNES screams]
[EREN] Come on!
Transform, goddamn it!
Don't let this be for nothing!
[HANNES screams, muffled]
[Squelch]
[Sobs]
[Laughs intensely]
[MIKASA]
Eren.
[EREN]
Look at you.
You haven't grown up
one goddamn bit!
You're still as useless
as you've ever been!
Nothing's changed!
[Sobs and  yells]
I'm sorry, Mother.
I still can't do anything.
No matter how hard I try,
I'm just a worthless little kid.
[MIKASA]
Eren.
Stop. That isn't true.
[MIKASA]
Hey. Thank you.
I've been meaning
to tell you that.
For fighting.
For always standing by me.
Thank you.
For pushing through.
For showing me
how to live with purpose.
I'm grateful.
My scarf.
For always
wrapping it around me.
Thank you.
[EREN sniffs]
[EREN] Mikasa. I will
always wrap your scarf.
Always and forever.
That's a promise!
[Yells]
[EREN growls]
[Bellows]
[ARMIN]
Huh?
Why're they--?
What's going on?
They're eating it!
Don't know,
don't care. Let's go!
Could be our only chance!
Right!
[YMIR]
That's what this is about.
No wonder Reiner was desperate
to get his hands on him.
Maybe there is
a future inside the walls.
I'll be damned.
[REINER] This isn't good. Why'd
things have to be this way?
Why'd the Coordinate
have to fall to him?
Unless we can get it back,
we're finished.
No two ways about it.
Of all the people in the world
that power could've gone to,
Eren is by far the worst.
Get away from us!
Rat bastards! I'll kill you
where you stand!
[REINER]
Son of a bitch. Bertholdt!
I can't protect him like this!
What the hell is going on?
[ARMIN]
Eren!
Can you ride?
[EREN]
Yeah!
Then hurry!
This may be our only window!
Soldiers, retreat!
[Yells]
[CHRISTA]
What is it?
Hey, ugly!
Get with the program!
We were given an order!
Please forgive me.
[Gasps]
Wait! What are you doing?
--Let her go!
--But she'll be killed!
[Yells]
[Roars]
♪
[ARMIN]
At the time,
Ymir's decision to turn
back puzzled me,
though I suspected it had
something to do with
why the Armored Titan
didn't give chase.
♪
[Distant panting]
[ALL panting]
[REINER]
I don't get it.
What the hell
possessed you to come back?
Uh. Can't say, really.
Probably wasn't
the smartest thing.
Seemed a little unfair
to send you guys home
empty-handed. Just, think of
me as a consolation prize.
Are you serious?
[YMIR] Look at it this way,
if you hadn't come
to bust up the wall,
who knows when my
nightmare would've ended?
I owed quite a debt.
This is me giving back
what I took from you.
'Least somebody knows
the shit you've been through.
Even if it is only me.
Yeah, well...
thank you. Sorry.
No worries.
Being a goddess had
its perks while it lasted.
[NARRATOR] With reports
maintaining the likelihood
of Wall Rose
having been compromised,
citizens of the region
were forced to take refuge
in a subterranean city within
the confines of Wall Sina.
However, though
emergency provisions
had been stockpiled
for the purpose,
with over half the
population relying on them,
rations could only last,
at most, a week.
Beyond that
lurked a terrible choice:
turn on each other like animals,
or face the prospect
of starvation.
To avoid a humanitarian crisis
of catastrophic proportions,
within a week of
the Titan onslaught,
authorities declared
Wall Rose secure.
[Knock, knock, knock]
Hange. Come in.
Pardon the intrusion, Erwin.
Commander Pyxis.
Glad we caught you.
[doorknob clicks, thuds]
Um, this is...
State your name.
Sir! Conny Springer, sir!
Hundred and fourth Cadet Corps!
Conny here is
originally from Ragako.
Ah, yes. Where the invasion
seems to have begun, correct?
[HANGE] Yes, sir.
In fact, he's corroborated
a valuable piece of evidence
in that regard.
I think you'll find his story
supports our hypothesis.
Soldier, if you would.
[EREN] I allowed myself to be
kidnapped. It's my fault.
Because of me
the Scouts lost over
half of their
veteran contingent.
All in a single
rescue attempt.
Still, though. There were no
causalities on the way back.
The Titans
completely ignored us.
They were too fixated
on Reiner and the others.
Jean and I, we mulled it over
between us once we got back.
[EREN]
Huh?
Hear me out.
Suppose they acted that way...
...because of you?
[EREN gasps]
[JEAN]
Just a thought, of course.
But as far as
an explanation,
it's about as good as we've got.
I'm not saying I envy
the position you're in.
Maybe all those people
really did die for nothing.
That all depends on you.
If you're really
worth the sacrifice,
you'd better prove it.
There's no time
for second-guessing.
You're right.
I have to be decisive.
If this is real--
if I can control Titans--
I have to plug up Wall Maria.
Then make Reiner answer
for what he's done.
People died for me. I have
to earn what they gave.
[PYXIS]
Come again?
You're saying the
Titans responsible for this
were the citizens of Ragako?
I see. So, in actuality,
Titans are human beings.
Well, we don't have proof yet.
[LEVI]
Great. Perfect.
I've spent all this time.
All this energy.
And the things I've been
carving through like carrion
were people.
Look, we don't know
for a certainty.
[CONNY sniffs]
Now what?
Um, excuse me.
What's with that smile?
Oh, it's nothing.
Just... seems to me
we've taken one more step
toward the truth.
Wow. One whole step, huh?
At this pace
we'll run out of people
before we actually reach it.
Not a good rate of return.
Everything comes at a price.
One day we'll get close
enough to break through.
The wall barring us
from the truth will tumble.
Not just yet.
♪ Closing Song